

# **ABOUT ME**

Software engineer with 8+ years of experience developing full-stack web services, apis, and websites for digital maps and navigation to help people explore the world. Coding is my craft and I plan to create more products users love. I'm passionate about learning new skills, being productive, and mentoring with care.

## CONTACT

LOCATION
Woodinville, WA

PHONE **757-561-8238** 

**EMAIL** 

msnider.software.engineer@gmail.com

WEBSITE

https://msnider.com

# MICHAEL SNIDER

Senior Software Engineer

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Senior Software Engineer, Microsoft

Aug 2016 – Present (8 years, 9 months)

Directions (2022 – Present). **Route enrichments** for maps, bing, and copilot working across multiple stacks. **Modernization** of bing route apis with .NET Core on Linux and gRPC for azure route apis. Polyline smoothness. 1% drop in bad requests. **Delayed segments** for mobile. Route debugger website. Commute ETA lookup on windows.

Beacon (2016 – 2021). **Device location** notification service for teams, family safety, bing, and outlook time to leave. Batch inference infrastructure. Location inference viewer website. **Home/work** apis.

Hackathon achievements. **Bring my pet home collar** (2019 One Week, 2<sup>nd</sup> place in Maps and Geospatial), Find my family (2017 Cortana Skills, 1<sup>st</sup> place), and Music ticket bot (2017 One Week, 2<sup>nd</sup> place Millennials).

#### Software Engineer Intern, Microsoft, Open Roads

2013 - 2015 (3 summers)

Microsoft (2015). **Location history** for Microsoft privacy dashboard. **Speed test** search result for Bing (hackathon).

Open Roads Consulting (2013, 2014). Event planning, travel time, and localization for the **traffic management system**. Website for quality assurance.

## **EDUCATION**

### B.S. Computer Science, University of Virginia

Aug 2012 - May 2016

3.941 GPA; Capstone map website for the Rivanna Trails Foundation; Undergraduate Thesis on societal values in online privacy.

#### Google UX Design Certificate, Coursera

Mar 2023 - Sep 2023

7-part course with 3 projects with hands-on experience with research, wireframes, mockups, prototypes, and usability testing.

### **SKILLS**

#### Languages

C#, TypeScript, Python, Java, CSS, HTML

## Software

Git, VS Code, Azure, CI/CD, K8s, Copilot, Figma

## Frameworks

ASP.NET Core, gRPC, Node.js, React, Vue.js